Ahhh... it's got that new movie smell.
Cars is a animation, adventure, comedy film directed by John Lasseter.
Lightning McQueen, a hotshot rookie race car driven to succeed, discovers that life is about the journey, not the
finish line, when he finds himself unexpectedly detoured in the sleepy Route 66 town of Radiator Springs.
On route across the country to the big Piston Cup Championship in California to compete
against two seasoned pros, McQueen gets to know the town's offbeat characters.
Lightning McQueen (voice), played by Owen Wilson.
Doc Hudson (voice), played by Paul Newman.
Sally Carrera (voice), played by Bonnie Hunt.
Mater (voice), played by Larry the Cable Guy.
Ramone (voice), played by Cheech Marin.
Luigi (voice), played by Tony Shalhoub.
Cars is a 2006 American animated sports comedy film produced by
Pixar Animation Studios for Walt Disney Pictures.
Directed by John Lasseter, who co-wrote it with Joe Ranft, Dan Fogelman, Kiel Murray, Phil Lorin, and Jorgen Klubien, the film stars Paul Newman (in his final film role) and Owen Wilson, alongside an ensemble voice cast consisting
of Bonnie Hunt, Larry the Cable Guy, Tony Shalhoub, Cheech Marin, Michael Wallis, George Carlin, Paul Dooley, Jenifer Lewis, Guido Quaroni, Michael Keaton, Katherine Helmond, John Ratzenberger and Richard Petty.
Set in a world populated entirely by anthropomorphic vehicles, the film follows a young self-obsessed racecar named Lightning
McQueen who, on the way to the most important race of his life, becomes stranded in a forgotten town along U.S.
Route 66 called Radiator Springs, where he learns about
friendship and begins to reevaluate his priorities.
Development for Cars started in 1998, after finishing the production of A Bug's Life, with a new script titled The
Yellow Car, which was about an electric car living in a gas-guzzling world with Klubien writing.
It was announced that the producers agreed that it could be the next Pixar film after A Bug's Life, scheduled for
a 1999 release, particularly around June 4; the idea was later scrapped in favor of Toy Story 2.
Shortly after, production was resumed with major script changes.
The film was inspired by Lasseter's experiences on a cross-country road trip.
Randy Newman composed the film's score, while artists such as Sheryl Crow, Rascal
Flatts, John Mayer and Brad Paisley contributed to the film's soundtrack.
Cars ultimately served as the final film independently produced by
Pixar after its purchase by Disney in January 2006.
Cars premiered on May 26, 2006, at Lowe's Motor Speedway in Concord, North Carolina and was theatrically released in the United States on June 9, to generally
positive reviews and commercial success, grossing $462 million worldwide against a budget of $120 million, becoming the sixth-highest-grossing film of 2006.
It received two nominations at the 79th Academy Awards, including Best Animated Feature, but lost to Happy Feet (but won
both the Annie Award for Best Animated Feature and the Golden Globe Award for Best Animated Feature Film).
The film was dedicated to Ranft, who died in a car
crash during the film's production.
The success of Cars launched a multimedia franchise, which includes two sequels: Cars 2 (2011) and Cars 3 (2017), as well
as two spin-off films produced by Disneytoon Studios: Planes (2013) and Planes: Fire and Rescue (2014).
The film explores themes of friendship, car race, sports, villain, success.
The tone is lighthearted.